USER INFO



Francis Santos Yokohama, Kanagawa, Japan

Level 2 Application Support Analyst SQL UNIX Java ITIL v3 Certified

Age: 31

Gender: Male

Nationality: Philippines

Location: Kanagawa

Visa Status: Permission to Work - Unrestricted: Spouse of Permanent Resident

English Ability: Fluent

Japanese Ability: Basic Level
Additional Languages: Tagalog, Native,

Title:

Level 2 Application Support Analyst SQL UNIX Java ITIL v3 Certified

Career Objective / Career Overview:

LIVE or Production Application Support Expert. ITIL® v3 Foundations Certified since 2014. Banking and Financial Applications IT Support Engineer. Functional and Technical Application Support Trainer. Technical Team Leading.

IT Application Support Engineer with more than 9 years experience in supporting customers and resolving business stakeholders' concerns regarding investment/retail banking software/applications/systems. IT DevOps Analyst in the Credit Risk Management group of Macquarie since 2015. Senior Application Support and stream lead since 2014. Experienced in technical team leading of junior resources. 3 years in Level 1 Application Support in Macquarie's Risk Management division. 3 years in Level 2 Application Support of Misys - a Treasury, Risk & Investment Management Solutions company for global banks. 1 year experience in software development for medium-sized enterprises using Java. Results oriented with a proven record of accomplishments and consistent contributions that increase efficiency and reduction of the total cost of application support through automation and process improvements. Assessed by the Australian Computer Society to be suitable as ICT Support Engineer of the ANZSCO Code.

I want to help you in your projects and automate your manual or repetitive tasks using Java, SQL, Unix scripting.

I want to help you in your day to day operations and your projects using my skills.

https://santosfrancisraymond.github.io

https://www.linkedin.com/in/francisraymondsantos

LIVEまたはプロダクションアプリケーションのサポートエキスパート。 ITIL®v3 Foundationsは2014年以来認証済みです。銀行業務および金融アプリケーションITサポートエンジニア。機能および技術アプリケーションサポートトレーナー。テクニカルチームリーディング。

ITアプリケーション・サポート・エンジニアであり、9年以上の経験を持ち、投資/リテール・バンキングのソフトウェア/アプリケーション/システムに関する顧客のサポートとビジネス関係者の懸念を解決してきました。2015年以来、マッコーリーの信用リスク管理グループのアナリストを務めています。2014年以降のシニアアプリケーションサポートとストリームリード。ジュニアリソースの技術チームの経験を積んだ経験があります。Macquarieのリスク管理部門のレベルパアプリケーションサポートで3年。レベル2のアプリケーションで3年間グローバルバンクの財務リスク管理ソリューション会社であるMisysのサポート。Javaを使用する中規模企業のソフトウェア開発で1年の経験結果は、自動化とプロセスの改善を通じて、アプリケーションのサポートの総コストの効率と削減を向上させ、実績と一貫した貢献を実証した結果を基にしています。ANZSCOコードのICTサポートエンジニアとして適しているとオーストラリアコンピュータ協会が評価しました。

私は、あなたのプロジェクトであなたを手伝って、Java、SQL、Unixスクリプトを使用して手動または反復タスクを自動化したいと思います。

自分のスキルを使って、日々の業務やプロジェクトでお手伝いしたいと思います。

https://santosfrancisraymond.github.io https://www.linkedin.com/in/francisraymondsantos

Education:

06 01 2003 - 11 01 2007 University of the Philippines Los Banos (フィリピンロスバノス大学)

Computer Science Bachelor's Degree

Work Experience:

11 01 2015 - 06 01 2017

Level 2 Application Support Analyst or ICT Support Engineer - ITIL v3 Certified Macquarie Offshore Services, PTY. LTD. - Philippines | Information Technology

Achievements: Collaboration Award - Feb 2017 - for being proactive in calling out emerging issues well in advance, pushing for process improvements and automation by working with developers in fully automating Credit jobs and increasing robustness.

Responsibilities: IT Support Engineer for Credit Risk Management of the bank. Vast experience in production environments. Ownership and resolution of issues, incidents and user requests by testing, analysis and deep investigation of source code (SQL, UNIX, Java). Application and infrastructure monitoring and resolution of issues reported by IT & Credit Risk Management Group. Driving various teams – Incident / Problem Management, DevOps, and Infrastructure teams - in resolving widespread critical system issues. Providing viable workarounds in a timely manner by scripting and/or debugging source code. Approval of production database changes of L1, L2 and L3 colleagues. Creating and reviewing technical documentation such as operational guides and manuals. Communicating with users and management regarding critical incidents and ensuring awareness and adherence to standards, procedures and quality control activities. 24x7 on-call contact. After hours/weekend support.

Change Management: Operational Acceptance Testing Manager. Collaborate with stakeholders and IT to review and approve production release plans to ensure smooth preparation, implementation, communications, technical and business verification, and transition of applications from project implementation to support. Testing and validating new software deployments, versions and patches.

Problem Management: Investigation of production failures and anomalies to determine the root cause of system issues. Writing well-defined bugs, providing a reproduction of the customer issue. Provide development

recommendations for resolution. Reduction of man-effort required via automating repetitive, manual, time & resource-consuming tasks by SQL and UNIX programming while ensuring day to day support is not disrupted.

Team Management: Developing, conducting and providing technical guidance and training in application software and operational procedures to L1, L2 and L3 staff in Philippines and India. Helping junior team members with their own investigations.

Technology used: Sybase SQL, Microsoft SQL, Java, UNIX & Windows, BMC Remedy 9, Atlassian JIRA & Confluence, Control-M Automation Batch Job Scheduling, Eclipse IDE, Apache Subversion, HP Diagnostics, HP SiteScope, Database Change Management

成果: 2017年2月のコラボレーション賞では、クレジット・ジョブを完全に自動化し、堅牢性を向上させるために開発者と協力して、プロセスの改善と自動化を推進しています。

責任:銀行の信用リスク管理のためのITサポートエンジニア。本番環境での豊富な経験ソースコード(SQL、UNIX、Java)のテスト、分析、詳細調査による問題、インシデントおよびユーザー要求の所有権と解決。IT &信用リスク管理グループによって報告された問題のアプリケーションおよびインフラストラクチャの監視と解決。広範な重要なシステム問題を解決するために、さまざまなチーム(インシデント/問題管理、開発チーム、インフラストラクチャチーム)を推進します。ソースコードのスクリプト作成やデバッグを行うことで、タイムリーに実行可能な回避策を提供します。 L1、L2、L3の同僚の生産データベース変更の承認。運用ガイドやマニュアルなどの技術文書の作成とレビュー重要なインシデントに関するユーザーや管理者とのコミュニケーション、標準、手順、品質管理活動への認識と遵守を確実にする。 24時間365日通話できます。時間/週末のサポートの後。

変更管理:運用受諾テストマネージャー。ステークホルダーとITと協力して、プロダクションリリース計画を 見直して承認し、スムーズな準備、実装、コミュニケーション、技術とビジネスの検証、およびプロジェクト 実施からサポートへのアプリケーションの移行を確実にします。新しいソフトウェアの展開、バージョン、お よびパッチのテストと検証。

問題管理:システムの問題の根本原因を特定するための、生産の失敗と異常の調査。よく定義されたバグを記述し、顧客の問題を再現します。解決のための開発勧告を提供する。反復、マニュアル、時間、リソースを消費するタスクをSQLとUNIXプログラミングで自動化し、日常的なサポートを確実にしながら人手を削減することができます。

チームマネジメント:フィリピンとインドのL1、L2、L3スタッフに対するアプリケーションソフトウェアと運用手順の技術指導と訓練を開発、実施、提供する。ジュニアチームのメンバーが独自の調査を行うのを手助けします。

使用技術: Sybase SQL、Microsoft SQL、Java、UNIX & Windows、BMC Remedy 9、Atlassian JIRAおよび Confluence、Control-M自動バッチジョブスケジューリング、Eclipse IDE、Apache Subversion、HP Diagnostics、HP SiteScope、データベース変更管理

06 01 2014 - 10 31 2015

Level 1 Senior Operations Application Support Analyst or ICT Support Engineer and Stream Lead Macquarie Offshore Services, PTY. LTD. - Philippines | Information Technology

Achievements: Corporate Operations Divisional Award Winner. Was seconded to India to perform functional and technical application training (in Risk Management) of Level 1 Operations staff (June 29, 2015 to July 17, 2015). Improved the quantity (200%) and quality of resolved tickets by the Level 1 Operations staff in India. Saved \$15434.00 worth of company's soft money via continuous improvements by slashing repetitive, manual, time & resource-consuming tasks of Level 1 Operations staff in Philippines and India using Control-M Batch Scheduling and SQL scripting. Acquired Certification in ITIL® Foundation in IT Service Management.

Responsibilities: Oversee the resolution of production incidents. Day to day Level 1 IT Operations, ticket allocation to junior members, Request Fulfillment, Incident Management, Change Management, and Escalation Management. 24x7 on-call escalation contact for critical issues.

Problem Management: Continuous improvements in Risk Management Group's Level 1 operations and processes. Improve customer satisfaction (CSAT) & operational SLA's. Delegate problem tasks to Level 1 Operations staff.

Team Management: Assign new requests to team members during daily team meetings. Continuous technical application training of all Level 1 Operations staff in Philippines and India. Ensure that all Level 1 Operations staff are across what needs to be done functionally for all issues, requests, problems and specially changes.

Collaborate daily with colleagues to present, review, meet and surpass the team's SLA's, KPI's and targets via a Visual Management Board.

Technology used: Sybase, Microsoft SQL, UNIX & Windows, BMC Remedy 7, Atlassian JIRA & Confluence, Control-M Automation Batch Job Scheduling, HP SiteScope, Database Change Management

業績:企業運営部門賞受賞者。レベル・運営スタッフ(2015年6月29日~2015年7月17日)の機能的および技術的なアプリケーショントレーニング(リスク管理における)をインドに実施しました。インドのレベルオペレーションスタッフによるチケットの量(200%)と品質の改善。

フィリピンとインドのレベルオペレーションスタッフのControl-MバッチスケジューリングとSQLスクリプティングを使用して、繰り返し、手動、時間、およびリソースを消費するタスクを削減することで、15434.00ドル相当のソフトマネーを継続的に改善しました。ITサービス管理におけるITIL®Foundationの認証取得

責任:生産事故の解決を監視する。レベルがOIT運用、ジュニアメンバーへのチケットの割り当て、リクエストの履行、インシデント管理、変更管理、エスカレーション管理などが含まれます。重大な問題については、24時間365日体制での電話によるエスカレーションを行います。

問題管理:リスク管理グループのレベル1の業務とプロセスの継続的な改善。顧客満足度(CSAT)と運用SLAを向上させます。問題のタスクをレベル1運用スタッフに委任する。

チーム管理:毎日のチームミーティング中にチームメンバーに新しい要求を割り当てます。フィリピンとインドのすべてのレベルオペレーションスタッフの継続的な技術的アプリケーショントレーニング。すべてのレベルオペレーションのスタッフが、すべての問題、要求、問題、および特別な変更に対して機能的に必要とされるものを超えていないことを確認します。チームのSLA、KPI、および目標をビジュアルマネジメントボードを通じて発表、レビュー、会合、上回るために、同僚と毎日協力してください。

使用されるテクノロジー: Sybase、Microsoft SQL、UNIXおよびWindows、BMC Remedy 7、Atlassian JIRAおよびConfluence、Control-M自動バッチジョブスケジューリング、HP SiteScope、データベース変更管理

06 01 2011 - 06 01 2014

Level 1 Application Support Analyst or ICT Support Engineer

Macquarie Offshore Services PTY. LTD. - Philippines | Information Technology

Achievements: Co-established the Level 1 IT Operations team in the Philippines.

On-boarded 30+ various investment banking applications (from Level 2 IT Operations) related to Online Services, Finance, Fixed Income, Currencies and Commodities, Human Resources, Credit Risk, Market Risk and Operational Risk applications. Expanded the Level 1 IT Operations team to India.

Specialization: Operations Monitoring Analyst for multiple banking applications.

Responsibilities: Knowledge Management. Continuous technical and functional application training of colleagues in Philippines and India. User Access Management, Request Fulfillment, SQL debugging, UNIX debugging, Incident Monitoring and Resolution, Ticket management, JIRA projects and bugs management, and Control-M batch job monitoring. Implement database changes following documentation. Fulfilled requests and resolved application incidents for Australia, America, London and Philippines business and IT stakeholders. Experienced working in APAC/ANZ, EMEA and Americas Shifts under a Shared Pool IT Operations Team.

Problem Management: Reduction of resource & time-consuming manual tasks of Level 1 through process improvements using Control-M Batch Scheduling while ensuring day to day support is not disrupted.

Technology used: Sybase, Microsoft SQL, UNIX & Windows, BMC Remedy 7, Atlassian JIRA & Confluence, Control-M Automation Batch Job Scheduling, HP SiteScope, Database Change Management

実績:レベル1のIT運用チームをフィリピンに共同設立しました。
オンラインサービス、ファイナンス、債券、通貨およびコモディティ、人事、信用リスク、市場リスクおよび

オペレーショナルリスクアプリケーションに関連する30以上の様々な投資銀行業務アプリケーション(レベル2のITオペレーションからの)レベル1のIT運用チームをインドに拡大しました。

専門分野:複数の銀行業務アプリケーションのOperations Monitoring Analyst。

責任:ナレッジマネジメント。フィリピンおよびインドの同僚の継続的な技術的および機能的なアプリケーショントレーニング。SQLデバッギング、UNIXデバッグ、インシデント監視と解決、チケット管理、JIRAプロジェクトとバグ管理、Control-Mバッチジョブ監視などの機能を備えています。ドキュメントにしたがってデータベースの変更を実装します。オーストラリア、アメリカ、ロンドン、フィリピンのビジネスおよびIT関係者向けに、要求を満たし、アプリケーションの問題を解決しました。Shared Pool IT Operationsチームの下で、APAC / ANZ、EMEA、およびAmericasのシフトに取り組んでいました。

問題管理: Control-Mバッチスケジューリングを使用してプロセスの改善を通じて、レベルのリソースおよび時間のかかる手作業を削減しながら、日々のサポートを損なうことはありません。

使用されるテクノロジー: Sybase、Microsoft SQL、UNIXおよびWindows、BMC Remedy 7、Atlassian JIRAおよびConfluence、Control-M自動バッチジョブスケジューリング、HP SiteScope、データベース変更管理

06 01 2008 - 05 01 2011

Level 2 Application Support Analyst or ICT Support Engineer

Misys International Banking Systems - Philippines | Information Technology

Achievements: Award of Merit for Commendable Contribution in Customer Support - Top RPG/CL Programming Trainee - Was awarded with a plaque of excellence for being part of the top 3 (out of ~30 AS400/RPG/CL programming trainees) during the 3-month programming training.

Support Consultant of the Month – resolved the most number of support tickets for the team for April 2010. Scripting of a utility for fixing retail deposit data corruption issues using AS400/RPG/CL.

Specialization: Equation Banking Software's modules like Equation Core Management System, Account Services, Watch List Checking, AML, SWIFT, Credit Risk Management, Retail Deposits and Retail Loans.

Responsibilities: Part of Rapid Response Team (RRT) who handle the most pressing / escalated / critical issues raised by clients. After Hours On-call Escalation Point for critical issues. Analysis of functional and technical cases and provides resolution in accordance with agreed customer metrics to ensure customer satisfaction. Email & Call customers from different banks and update accurate information in the call logging system (SupportForce.Com) so that customers can see progress on the support cases. Identify Professional Services or Product Sales opportunities arising from customer calls and referring these to the appropriate groups for action in order to drive increased revenue.

Act as Account Manager to banks that have huge number of cases logged and/or have escalated issues. Test patches & create fixes for critical issues. Create testing and installation documents for customers' or bank's use.

Technology used: Equation Banking, SQL Server, Meridian Link, IBM Websphere, Fircosoft, AS400/RPG/CL programming.

実績:3年間の最優秀3名(AS400/RPG/CLプログラマー研修生のうち30名)のトップ3に選ばれたことで、最高の栄誉を授与されました。月のプログラミング訓練。

今月のサポートコンサルタント - AS400 / RPG / CLを使用してリテール預金データの破損問題を修正するためのユーティリティのスクリプティング。

スペシャライゼーション: Equation Core Management System、口座サービス、ウォッチリストチェック、AML、SWIFT、信用リスク管理、リテール預金、リテールローンなどの方程式バンキングソフトウェアのモジュール。

責任:クライアントによって提起された最も緊急の/エスカレートされた/重大な問題を処理する迅速対応チーム (RRT) の一部。営業時間外コールのエスカレーションクリティカルな問題を指摘します。機能的および技術的なケースの分析を行い、合意された顧客評価基準に基づいて解決を提供し、顧客満足度を確保します。電子メールと通話記録システム (SupportForce.Com) で正確な情報を更新して、顧客がサポートケースの進捗状

況を確認できるようにします。お客様の電話から生じるプロフェッショナルサービスまたはプロダクトセールスの機会を特定し、これらのグループを適切なグループに照会して収益を増やしてください。

膨大な数のケースが記録されている、および/またはエスカレートされた問題を抱えている銀行に対して、アカウントマネージャーとして行動する。パッチをテストし、重大な問題の修正を作成します。顧客または銀行の使用のためのテストおよびインストール文書を作成する。

使用されるテクノロジー:方程式バンキング、SQL Server、経絡リンク、IBM Websphere、Fircosoft、AS400/RPG/CLプログラミング。

04 01 2007 - 04 01 2008

Java Junior Analyst Programmer

Laserite Systems Inc. | Information Technology

Achievements: As a university student, worked part-time for 6 months in a start-up company while simultaneously completing my thesis/special project. Eventually absorbed by the company and worked full-time as a Junior Java Developer for another 6 months.

Responsibilities: Development, debugging, testing and quality assurance of software for medium-sized enterprises.

Projects:

- Employee Management System for Pampanga's Best
- Biometric Fingerprint Scanner for Pampanga's Best
- · Inventory System for Auto Parts for PGA Cars.

Technology used: Java, PostgreSQL, JDBC, Enrage Platform, JUnit, Jude, Hibernate, Eclipse IDE, SQL Server Studio

成果:大学生として、スタートアップ会社で6ヶ月間アルバイトをしながら、同時に論文/特別プロジェクトを完成させました。最終的に会社に吸収され、ジュニアJava開発者としてフルタイムでさらに6ヶ月間働いた。

責任:中小企業向けソフトウェアの開発、デバッグ、テスト、品質保証

プロジェクト:

パンパンガのベストのための従業員管理システム パンパンガのベストバイオメトリック指紋スキャナ PGA車のための自動車部品の在庫システム。

使用技術:Java、PostgreSQL、JDBC、Enrage Platform、JUnit、Jude、Hibernate、Eclipse IDE、SQL Server Studio

Total Years of Experience:

9

Skills:

IT Service Management, Request fulfillment, Incident management, Change management, Knowledge management, Problem management, Asset management, Continuous improvement process, Operational Acceptance Testing, Operating Systems and Servers, Windows, Linux, UNIX, JBoss, Relational Databases, Sybase SQL, Sybase Adaptive Server, Microsoft SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Non-relational Databases, NoSQL, NIQL, MongoDB, Couchbase, Programming, Java, JUnit, SQL scripting, UNIX scripting, Eclipse IDE, HTML5, Bootstrap, Ionic, CSS3, IBM AS400, IBM RPG/CL, Qt Framework, SDLC, Automation/Monitoring, BMC Control-M, HP SiteScope, HP Diagnostics, Ticket Management, Atlassian, JIRA, BMC Remedy 9, SalesForce/SupportForce, オペレーティングシステムとサーバ, リレーショナルデータベース, Sybase, ITサービス管理, 要求処理, インシデント管理, 変更管理, ナレッジ管理, 問題管理, 資産管理, 継続的改善プロセスSQL, 非リレーショナルデータベ

ース, プログラミング, SQLスクリプト, UNIXスクリプト, ブートストラップ, IBM RPG / CL, Qtフレームワーク, オートメーション/モニタリング, HP診断, チケット管理, SalesForce / SupportForce

Additional Information:

Japan. Computers. Music. Drums. Travelling. Video Editing. Basketball. Computer Games. Underwater Diving

日本。コンピュータ。音楽。ドラム。旅行。ビデオ編集。バスケットボール。コンピューターゲーム。水中ダイビング

2010 Professional Association of Diving Instructors – PADI - Member 2006 UPLB Green Mountain Circle Cordilleran Society – Member

2005 UP Jammers' Club

• POUND 4 POUND - Project Committee Head

2004 UPLB Computer Science Society

- · Computer Science Week Games Day Head
- PalaCASan Sports Event Project Committee Head

2010年ダイビングインストラクターの専門家協会 - PADI - 会員 2006年UPLBグリーンマウンテンサークルコーディユラン協会 - 会員 2005 UP Jammers 'Club ・ポンド4ポンド - プロジェクト委員長 2004年UPLBコンピュータサイエンス協会 ・コンピュータサイエンスウィーク - ゲームデーヘッド

•PalaCASanスポーツイベント - プロジェクト委員長

Certified in ITIL® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management

Certification Authority: PEOPLECERT License Number: GCI-2014-5646

Certification

 $\label{lem:url:like} \textbf{URL: http://www.peoplecert.org/en/Candidates/Certificate_Verification/Pages/Certificate_Verifica$

English

IELTS General Training Exam Results as of 15 Mar 2017

Listening: 8.0 Reading: 9.0 Speaking: 7.0 Writing: 7.0

Overall Band Score: 8.0

CEFR Level: C1

Collaboration Award, Macquarie - Risk and Compliance - Corporate Operations Group - Technology Awarded: Feb 2017 Was awarded for commitment to our customers and DevOps in his role as the primary L2 resource for Credit, Groupwide, and PCM. The Credit Risk Management business appreciated the more in-depth analysis done by Francis on user queries which shows how well he collaborates with SMEs. He was also proactive in calling out emerging issues well in advance, pushing for process improvements and automation.

Macquarieコラボレーション賞 - リスクとコンプライアンス - コーポレートオペレーショングループ - テクノロジー

受賞:2017年2月クレジット、グループワイド、PCMの主要なL2リソースとしての顧客および開発部門へのコミットメントとして授与されました。信用リスク管理事業は、中小企業との協力がどの程度うまくいっているかを示すユーザーの質問に対して、Francisが行ったより詳細な分析を評価しました。また、プロセスの改善と自動化を推進するために、新興の問題を事前に呼び出すことに積極的でした。

Corporate Operations Divisional Award, Macquarie - Institutional Business Support - Corporate Operations

Group - Technology Awarded: Jul 2015 Was seconded to India to perform functional and technical application training (in Risk Management) of Level 1 Operations staff (June 29, 2015 to July 17, 2015). Improved the quantity (200%) and quality of resolved tickets by the Level 1 Operations staff in India.

コーポレートオペレーション部門賞、マッコーリー - 法人向けビジネスサポート - コーポレートオペレーショングループ - テクノロジー

受賞:2015年7月

レベル1運営スタッフ(2015年6月29日~2015年7月17日)の機能的および技術的なアプリケーショントレーニング(リスク管理における)をインドに実施しました。インドのレベル1オペレーションスタッフによるチケットの量(200%)と品質の改善。

Award of Merit for Commendable Contribution in Customer Support, Misys Philippines - Equation Customer Support Division

Awarded: Oct 2008

Was awarded with a plaque of excellence for being part of the top 3 (out of 30 RPG/CL/AS400 programming trainees) during the 3-month programming training.

Misys Philippines - 顧客サポート部門の称賛の賜物であるメリット賞

受賞:2008年10月

3ヶ月間のプログラミング訓練の最中にトップ3(30人のRPG / CL / AS400プログラミング研修生のうちの1人)に参加するための優秀賞を授与されました。